I am near my limit, it's true.
But the same thing
goes for you too.
Even if you can hide your
decaying body with clothing,
you cannot disguise the smell.
Hohenheim...
You're right.
This is the first time in hundreds of years
that we've seen each other.
We should have a nice long talk with each other.
Besides, I haven't even
tried out this young body.
Sorry, but I have a wife.
Yes, and I have had husbands.
Many, many, many of them.
If I hadn't, then the secret of my slowly aging body would have become known.
For me, Trisha was my first and my last—
the first woman I ever loved.
Oh, my.
Four hundred years ago,
when we first met,
and I didn't know any better,
you whispered words of love to me.
Or perhaps I'm remembering wrong.
Let's stop this.
On that day, four hundred years ago,
we finally made it.
There were those who had escaped the witch hunts
and those who were just waiting for death from the black plague.
Over and over, we used their lives
in our experiments
and obtained a Philosopher's Stone.
But the reaction from that transmutation left you nearly dead,
so using the Philosopher's Stone, I bonded your soul to the body of another person.
And so, we had obtained eternal life.
You mean, you've used
the Philosopher's Stone
to transfer your souls around
over and over again?
Yes, we have.
You don't mean...
the whole reason why
you had us seek out someone who could make a Philosopher's Stone was...
I found that it became necessary, once Hohenheim of Light left me.
Why? Why did you
disappear from my sight?
Dante,
there is no such thing
as eternal life.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who obtain it are set free from the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
There is no need to pay a price
in order to obtain something, either.
We sought it and found it.
Aah! You can't put that much salt in, and you've got too much cream!
Cooking is a science,
just like making Automail.
You have to make things exact and according to calculations.
And with this newly made oven of mine,
it will turn out perfectly!
With this knob, you can adjust it to whatever temperature you want in a snap.
It has a timer function you can set for the right number of minutes.
It has this heat-resistant glass, so you can see what's happening inside at any time.
It's absolutely perfect!
Cooking is an art.
It's like literature.
It takes imagination and a sense of adventure that cannot be pigeonholed.
Cooking is a science!
No, it's not. It's an art!
You get it.
I'm a guest, so you go ahead.
No, no, we're like family now—
Hurry and answer that!
Right!
Hello?
The Elric brothers are there, right?
Shaw-chan?
Yes.
Their voice was strange for some reason,
but they said their name
was Shaw-chan.
Shaw-chan...
Anyhow, they said to tell you
they'd like to see you.
Whenever you came back here would be fine, they said.
And another thing—they were crying.
Shaw...
Someone you know?
Mm-mm! Wow, that looks delicious! Brother is going to be thrilled!
Ah, it's Brother!
Brother!
What happened to
your clothes?
Brother?
Oh, just went on a little outing.
I made it look like we were setting out to head north.
I deliberately left some eyewitnesses, and on the way back, I fell down.
Then I should have gone with you.
And what if you really were
discovered by the homunculi?
So, did anything happen?
We seem to have gotten a strange phone call a little while ago.
It's nobody we know!
It was probably
the police trying to find us, you know?
You don't say.
I'm hungry!
I'm the one who recommended
Edward Elric to be a State Alchemist!
What shame he has brought to me!
Are we certain that the boy was
connected with the uprising in Liore?
According to the report, a year ago in Liore,
he exposed a priest of Leto
who had been misusing alchemy.
However, the truth of the matter is,
the priest continued to thrive following that,
and consequently, a situation arose
where we had to intervene militarily.
That intervention was overzealously enforced, and the civilians turned against the military.
Are you criticizing my mission strategy?
Now, hold on, everyone.
Looking at Colonel Mustang's
service record,
it is clear that he is an excellent soldier who has sworn his loyalty to the military.
However,
I do not understand why you would put
a halt to the search for the Elric brothers.
We thought the Elric brothers would return to their home,
so we put out a
dragnet in the east.
However, they appear to have gone straight north.
North? To Drachma?
So that's it! They're in contact with those savages, are they?!
Major Armstrong's squad has begun a search in the north.
However, I have learned of
an even more serious matter,
which is why I have returned.
A serious matter?
If you like, I could have everyone step outside.
No, this is about your secretary, Captain Juliet Douglas.
Well, this is sudden.
She is on leave right now.
What about her?
I have serious doubts
about her military service.
What's more, there is a possibility that she was involved in the circumstances
surrounding the murder of Brigadier General Hughes.
Oh, are you certain of that?
You have a crush on her, all right!
Come to think of it, we all heard.
You've gone and done
something bold again, huh?
Why would you deliberately
do something to provoke him?
It doesn't matter whether or not
the Führer is a homunculus.
Still, those who call themselves homunculi
have spent a long time sacrificing human lives
to create a Philosopher's Stone.
If that's the case, then there is a possibility that the civil war in Ishbal
was engineered in order to
bring about a Philosopher's Stone.
They would intentionally start a war?
Why is it that people seek the Philosopher's Stone?
Riches... glory... domination...
Eternal life...
Desperation.
When a person loses
those who are around them
and is caught up in despair,
they seek the Philosopher's Stone
as their only hope.
In the middle of the
irregular conditions of war,
the morals that say that one must not sacrifice the lives of others vanish.
It is true that ever since
the current Führer took power,
the country has been at war
somewhere or other.
And we've won every one of them.
I don't have any complaints over going to war.
We are soldiers.
But when it's about making people stand at the brink of despair
in order to get a
Philosopher's Stone created...
Ed! Al!
How long are you
going to sleep in?!
Sorry!
It's all right.
A simple chemical reaction like this
is one of the fundamentals of alchemy.
There.
Wh-What is that?
It's me, Winry!
Al?
I encased Al snugly inside bronze.
There aren't any seams, so as long as
they don't break it in half,
there's no way
they'll know it's him.
You're leaving again?
There's something
that we have to do.
I know! You're going to
return Al to normal, right?
You can hide here and do your research, can't you?
Are you going to take revenge for Hughes-san?
No, we won't take revenge.
Otherwise, Scar's death
will have been meaningless.
Then...
Even so,
there's still something
that we must do.
Something more important than revenge, and what you've been searching for?
Yow-ow-ow-ow!
Wh-What are you doing?!
I'm doing your braid for you.
Th-That's okay, I'll do it later.
I'll do it for you!
O-Okay...
It's not anything dangerous, right?
Brother, where could Dad have gone?
Just keep quiet.
Deterioration of the soul?
As our souls have been repeatedly transferred into different bodies, they have eroded.
Our souls no longer have the power to sustain their bodies.
Dante, we are going to perish like this.
No, I just need the Philosopher's Stone.
I can always take a new body.
It will happen again immediately after moving to that body,
and the same will be true of the next body.
Then I'll move into
another new body!
What about the Philosopher's Stone?
You must have used the last bit I left you
to transfer into that body.
That is why those boys have made the next Stone for me.
The Ishbalan man has turned your son
into a Philosopher's Stone.
Dante-sama, then it really is true?
Don't you get it yet?
When I saw Edward and Alphonse, I should have realized...
what they had done.
No, I knew.
But I didn't want to believe it.
Trisha...
You will always be dear to me.
Thank you, Hohenheim of Light.
To think that you could be beaten by a homunculus, of all things.
Ever since you left, I've been
doing some research of my own.
That gate, which is the source of power for alchemy—
What lies on the other side of it?
Isn't there a way
to open the gate?
The gate is inside of us.
And so, someone whose bond between body, mind, and soul is still weak,
say, as is the case for this baby,
is able to call forth the gate
even stronger.
Shall we perform an experiment,
to see what the other side of the gate is like?
Tri...
I'm sure that Ed and Al are all right.
They are... your children.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
It's okay, Wrath.
You don't ever have to go back to the other side of that gate.
Bring the Philosopher's Stone here,
Wrath, Sloth, and Lust.
So that you...
can be reborn once again?
Once I have the Philosopher's Stone, and after my soul has been bonded,
I really will turn
you all into humans.
However,
it all depends on my mood.
Here is your baby.
You have to eat more,
or you won't be able to fit into my dress sizes, you know.
Search carefully!
There's a possibility that they've changed their hair and eye color.
A large man and a runt.
The runt is as small as a bean sprout, so don't overlook him.
He's not the one, huh? The one we're searching for is as small as a baby ant.
Commander!
We found an odd bronze sculpture.
How big is it?
It looks larger than the suit of armor in the dispatch.
Hmm, just to be safe,
we'll smash it with a hammer!
Break it.
Here goes!
You!
You're that man from before!
You're the bean sprout we heard about!
Al, let's go!
Wait, Brother!
A-After them!
Al, go on ahead!
Brother, I can very well...
Just get going!
Thanks, Brother.
But...
Al, don't use any alchemy.
Why not?
I remembered the gate.
And besides, I'm a Philosopher's Stone.
I can probably do it,
just like you do, Brother.
You don't have to!
We don't know what will happen if you use alchemy.
We'll take our time to research it,
and I'll return you to your original body.
We'll take everything from there.
Brother, where are you going?
It's like that bastard said, right?
There's someone pulling
the strings of the homunculi.
There's something I'm going to need
in order to find them.
I'm going too.
You can stay.
I'll be right back.
Brother...
You can look after things here by yourself, right?
The two of us have been ordered to take command of the expeditionary forces in the north, huh?
Then it's settled.
Yeah.
They have to know we've been in contact with Ed and Al,
because of the matter
with the secretary.
And yet, they're sending us off to the front,
without the least bit of censure.
If they were going to shut us up,
they could just attack us here in Central.
There is the matter of Hughes, and all.
If they were to use the same tactic again,
it would arouse suspicion.
On the battlefield, they can kill us
whenever they please.
Afterwards, even if they do turn up
any documents, they can just sit on them.
Still, even now, I can't
believe that he could be...
No matter how many times I read over the materials that Scieszka gave me,
I couldn't unravel it.
This was the final
part of the puzzle.
You've given yourself away, haven't you,
you miserable homunculus?
I didn't think you
would have stayed here.
You never know what's going on
right under your nose.
Besides, I wanted to look through
some of the things that Dante had.
Did you find anything?
I'll tell you later.
More importantly,
what are you here for?
I think it will just
get you mad at me again.
Never mind that, tell me.
There's something that I absolutely have to get my hands on.
Sensei, is there any part of your
dead baby's body still remaining?
You're going to fight them?
Yes.
Excuse me...
It's me.
It's so... so good of you
to come, Alphonse-kun.
Please teach me how to use the Philosopher's Stone.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 46: "Human Transmutation"
Why do you want to
become human—
something so worthless?